So, I'd like to spend a few minutes with you folks today
أودّ قضاء بضعة دقائق معكم اليوم
imagining what our planet might look like in a thousand years.
فلنتخيّل ما قد يبدو عليه كوكبنا بعد ألف سنة.
But before I do that,
ولكن قبل أن أقوم بذلك،
I need to talk to you about synthetic materials like plastics,
أنا بحاجة لأتحدث إليكم عن المواد الإصطناعية مثل البلاستيك،
which require huge amounts of energy to create
والتي تتطلب صناعتها كميات هائلة من الطاقة
and, because of their disposal issues,
وبسبب صعوبة التخلّص منها،
are slowly poisoning our planet.
فهي مسؤولة عن تسمّم كوكبنا.
I also want to tell you and share with you
وأريد أيضا أن أخبركم وأشاطركم
how my team and I
المدى الذّي قمت فيه وزملائي في الفريق
have been using mushrooms over the last three years.
باستخدام الفطر على مدى السنوات الثلاث الماضية.
Not like that. (Laughter)
ليس بهذا الشّكل. (ضحك)
We're using mushrooms to create an entirely new class of materials,
نستخدم الفطر لصناعة نوع جديد تماما من المواد،
which perform a lot like plastics during their use,
التي تشبه في استخدامها البلاستيك إلى حدّ كبير،
but are made from crop waste
ولكنّها مصنوعة من نفايات المحاصيل
and are totally compostable at the end of their lives.
وتتحوّل في نهاية المطاف بالكامل إلى سماد.
(Cheering)
(هتاف)
But first,
ولكن أولا ،
I need to talk to you about what I consider one of the most egregious offenders
أنا بحاجة لأتحدث إليكم عن ما أعتبره أحد أفظع الجناة
in the disposable plastics category.
في فئة البلاستيك القابل للتصرف.
This is a material you all know is Styrofoam,
وهي المادّة التي نعلمها جميعا وهي الستايروفوم،
but I like to think of it as toxic white stuff.
ولكن أود أن أتعامل معها كأحد المواد السامة البيضاء.
In a single cubic foot of this material --
قدم مكعب واحدة من هذه المادّة --
about what would come around your computer or large television --
تقريبا ما يكفي لتغليف جهاز كمبيوتر أو تلفزيون كبير الحجم --
you have the same energy content
يحتوي تقريبا نفس القدر من الطاقة
of about a liter and a half of petrol.
الموجود في حوالي لتر ونصف من البنزين.
Yet, after just a few weeks of use,
حتى الآن ، وبعد أسابيع قليلة من الاستخدام ،
you'll throw this material in the trash.
سوف تقوم برمي هذه المواد في سلة المهملات.
And this isn't just found in packaging.
ولا نحصل على هذا فقط في موادّ التعبئة.
20 billion dollars of this material is produced every year,
يتم إنتاج ما قيمته 20 مليار دولار من هذه المواد في كل عام ،
in everything from building materials to surfboards
في كل شيء، من مواد البناء لألواح التزلج على الماء
to coffee cups to table tops.
لفناجين القهوة لغلاف الطّاولات.
And that's not the only place it's found.
وهذا ليس المكان الوحيد لوجودها.
The EPA estimates, in the United States,
تقديرات وكالة حماية البيئة في الولايات المتحدة ،
by volume, this material occupies 25 percent of our landfills.
من حيث الحجم ، تحتل هذه المواد 25 في المئة من مصابّ القمامة لدينا.
Even worse is when it finds its way into our natural environment --
والأسوأ من ذلك هو عندما تجد طريقها إلى بيئتنا الطبيعية --
on the side of the road or next to a river.
على جانب الطريق أو بجانب النهر.
If it's not picked up by a human, like me and you,
إذا لم يتمّ إلتقاطها من قبل الإنسان، مثلي أومثلكم،
it'll stay there for thousands and thousands of years.
فإنّها سوف تبقى هناك لآلاف وآلاف السنين.
Perhaps even worse
ربما أسوأ
is when it finds its way into our oceans, like in the great plastic gyre,
وعندما تجد طريقها إلى محيطاتنا ، تماما مثل مُفَتّتات البلاستيك الكبيرة،
where these materials are being mechanically broken
حيث يتم تفتيت هذه المواد ميكانيكيا
into smaller and smaller bits,
إلى أجزاء أصغر وأصغر،
but they're not really going away.
ولكنها لن تذهب في الواقع بعيدا.
They're not biologically compatible.
إنّها لا تتطابق من الناحية البيولوجية.
They're basically fouling up
إنها تقوم بتسميم
Earth's respiratory and circulatory systems.
كوكب الأرض في الجهاز التنفسي والدورة الدموية.
And because these materials are so prolific,
ولأن هذه المواد متوافرة جدا،
because they're found in so many places,
لأنّها موجودة في أماكن عدّة،
there's one other place you'll find this material, styrene,
هناك مكان آخر ستجد فيه هذه المادّة، الستايرين،
which is made from benzene, a known carcinogen.
المصنوعة من البنزين ، وهي مادة مسرطنة معروفة.
You'll find it inside of you.
سوف تجدها بداخلك.
So, for all these reasons,
لذلك ، لهذه الأسباب جميعا ،
I think we need better materials,
أعتقد أننا في حاجة لمواد أفضل،
and there are three key principles we can use to guide these materials.
وهناك ثلاثة مبادئ رئيسية يمكننا استخدامها لتعريف هذه المواد.
The first is feedstocks.
الأول هو المواد الأولية.
Today, we use a single feedstock, petroleum,
اليوم ،نحن نستخدم عنصرا واحدا، البترول ،
to heat our homes, power our cars
لتدفئة منازلنا ، وتزويد سياراتنا بالطّاقة
and make most of the materials you see around you.
ولصناعة معظم المواد التي تراها حولك.
We recognize this is a finite resource,
ونحن ندرك أنّ هذا مورد محدود،
and it's simply crazy to do this, to put a liter and a half of petrol in the trash
وأنّ القيام بوضع لتر ونصف من البنزين في سلة المهملات هو ببساطة محض الجنون،
every time you get a package.
في كل مرة تحصل على مُغلّف.
Second of all, we should really strive to use far less energy
ثانيا ، ينبغي علينا أن نسعى حقا إلى استخدام الطاقة أقل بكثير
in creating these materials.
أثناء صناعة هذه المواد.
I say far less, because 10 percent isn't going to cut it.
أقول أقل بكثير ، وذلك لأن 10 في المئة لا تكفي.
We should be talking about half, a quarter,
ينبغي لنا أن نتحدث عن نصف، أو ربع،
one-tenth the energy content.
أو عُشر محتوى الطاقة.
And lastly, and I think perhaps most importantly,
وأخيرا، وأعتقد ربما الأهم من ذلك ،
we should be creating materials
ينبغي أن نصنع موادا
that fit into what I call nature's recycling system.
تنسجم مع ما أسميه نظام إعادة التدوير في الطبيعة.
This recycling system has been in place for the last billion years.
نظام إعادة التدوير هذا موجود منذ بلايين السنين.
I fit into it, you fit into it,
أنا أنسجم معه، و أنت كذلك،
and a hundred years tops, my body can return to the Earth with no preprocessing.
وبعد مائة سنة على أقصى تقدير ، يمكن لجسدي العودة إلى الأرض بدون أيّ تحضير مسبق.
Yet that packaging I got in the mail yesterday
إلى حدّ الآن، تبقى موادّ التغليف التّي حصلت عليها في البريد أمس
is going to last for thousands of years.
آلاف السنين.
This is crazy.
هذا جنون.
But nature provides us with a really good model here.
لكن الطبيعة توفر لنا نموذجا جيدا حقا هنا.
When a tree's done using its leaves --
عندما تتخلّص الشجرة من أوراقها --
its solar collectors, these amazing molecular photon capturing devices --
مُجمّعات الطاقة الشمسية فيها، وجهاز الإلتقاط الفوتونيّ المذهل ذلك --
at the end of a season,
في نهاية الموسم،
it doesn't pack them up, take them to the leaf reprocessing center
لا تقوم بحزمها ، و من ثمّ نقلها الى مركز اعادة معالجة النبات
and have them melted down to form new leaves.
و تقوم بإعادة تدويرها وصولا الى شكل أوراق جديدة.
It just drops them, the shortest distance possible,
فإنّها تقوم بإسقاطها فقط ، أقصر مسافة ممكنة،
to the forest floor,
الى طابق الغابات،
where they're actually upcycled into next year's topsoil.
حيث تتمّ إعادة تدويرها في التربة السطحية للعام المقبل.
And this gets us back to the mushrooms.
وهذا يعود بنا إلى الفطر.
Because in nature,
لأنه في الطبيعة ،
mushrooms are the recycling system.
يمثّل الفطر نظام إعادة التدوير.
And what we've discovered
وما اكتشفناه
is, by using a part of the mushroom you've probably never seen --
هو أنّه، باستخدام جزء من الفطر ربما لم تروه من قبل --
analogous to its root structure; it's called mycelium --
مشابهة لبنية جذورها ، يدعا أفطورة --
we can actually grow materials
يمكننا أن نجعل تلك المواد تنموا فعلا
with many of the same properties of conventional synthetics.
مع العديد من الخصائص المشابهة للمواد التركيبية التقليدية.
Now, mycelium is an amazing material,
الآن ، الأفطورة هي مادة مذهلة ،
because it's a self-assembling material.
لأنها مادة ذاتيّة التجميع.
It actually takes things we would consider waste --
إنّها تأخذ الاشياء التي ننظر إليها في الواقع كنفايات --
things like seed husks or woody biomass --
أشياء مثل قشور البذور أو كتلة حيوية خشبية --
and can transform them into a chitinous polymer,
ويمكن تحويلها إلى بوليمر كيتيني ،
which you can form into almost any shape.
والتي يمكن تشكيلها إلى أي شكل تقريبا.
In our process,
في عمليتنا،
we basically use it as a glue.
نحن نستخدمها كمادّة لاصقة.
And by using mycelium as a glue,
وباستخدام الأفطورة كمادّة لاصقة،
you can mold things just like you do in the plastic industry,
يمكنك تشكيل الأشياء تماما مثلما تفعل في صناعة البلاستيك،
and you can create materials with many different properties,
ويمكنك إنشاء مواد ذات خصائص مختلفة وكثيرة،
materials that are insulating, fire-resistant,
مواد عازلة، مقاومة للحريق،
moisture-resistant, vapor-resistant --
مقاومة للرطوبة ، مقاومة للبخار --
materials that can absorb impacts, that can absorb acoustical impacts.
مواد يمكنها أن تمتص الصّدمات، يمكنها أن تمتصّ الموجات الصوتية.
But these materials are grown from agricultural byproducts,
لكن هذه المواد تنموا من المخلفات الزراعية،
not petroleum.
وليس البترول.
And because they're made of natural materials,
ولأنها مصنوعة من المواد الطبيعية،
they are 100 percent compostable
فهي تتحوّل بالكامل إلى سماد
in you own backyard.
في الفناء الخلفي لديك.
So I'd like to share with you the four basic steps
لذلك أود أن أطلعكم على الخطوات الأساسية الأربعة
required to make these materials.
اللازمة لصناعة هذه المواد.
The first is selecting a feedstock,
أوّلا هو إختيار المادّة الأوليّة،
preferably something that's regional, that's in your area, right --
يُفضل أن تكون مادّة محليّة، ومتوفّرة في منطقتك --
local manufacturing.
تصنيع محليّ.
The next is actually taking this feedstock and putting in a tool,
التّالي هو أخذ الموادّ الأوليّة، ووضعها في آلة،
physically filling an enclosure, a mold,
ووضعها في وعاء، قالب،
in whatever shape you want to get.
أيا كان الشكل الذي تريد الحصول عليه.
Then you actually grow the mycelium through these particles,
من ثم تنمو الأفطورة من خلال هذه الجزيئات ،
and that's where the magic happens,
وعندها يحدث السحر،
because the organism is doing the work in this process,
لأن الجسم هو الذي يقوم بالعمل في هذه العملية،
not the equipment.
لا المعدات.
The final step is, of course, the product,
والخطوة الأخيرة هي ، بطبيعة الحال ، المُنتج ،
whether it's a packaging material, a table top, or building block.
سواء أكان ذلك مواد تغليف ، وهو أعلى الجدول، أو لبنة.
Our vision is local manufacturing,
وتتمثل رؤيتنا في التصنيع المحلي ،
like the local food movement, for production.
مثل حركة المواد الغذائية المحلية ، للإنتاج.
So we've created formulations for all around the world
لذا قمنا بإنشاء تركيبات لجميع أنحاء العالم
using regional byproducts.
بإستخدام المنتجات الإقليمية.
If you're in China, you might use a rice husk
إذا كنت في الصين ، قد ترغب في استخدام قشر الأرز
or a cottonseed hull.
أو قشور القطن.
If you're in Northern Europe or North America,
إذا كنت في شمال أوروبا أو أميركا الشمالية ،
you can use things like buckwheat husks or oat hulls.
يمكنك استخدام أشياء مثل قشور الحنطة السوداء أو قشر الشوفان.
We then process these husks with some basic equipment.
يمكننا إثر ذلك القيام بالعملية مع بعض المعدات الأساسية.
And I want to share with you a quick video from our facility
وأريد أن أطلعكم على شريط فيديو قصيرمن منشأتنا
that gives you a sense of how this looks at scale.
والتي تمنحك شعورا كيف يمكن أن يبدو هذا على نطاق واسع.
So what you're seeing here is actually cotton hulls from Texas, in this case.
لذلك ما ترونه هنا هو في الواقع قشور القطن من ولاية تكساس ، في هذه الحالة.
It's a waste product.
إنها نفايات.
And what they're doing in our equipment
وما يفعلونه باستعمال معداتنا
is going through a continuous system,
يمر بنظام مستمر،
which cleans, cooks, cools
يقوم بالتنظيف والطبخ والتبريد
and pasteurizes these materials,
وتعقيم هذه المواد،
while also continuously inoculating them with our mycelium.
ويقوم في نفس الوقت أيضا بتلقيح الأفطورة باستمرار.
This gives us a continuous stream of material
وهذا يعطينا دفقا مستمرّا من المواد
that we can put into almost any shape,
والذي يمكن تشكيله إلى أي شكل تقريبا،
though today we're making corner blocks.
على الرغم من أنّنا إلى اليوم نحن ننتج كتلا ركنية.
And it's when this lid goes on the part,
وعندما يظهر هذا الغطاء من الجانب،
that the magic really starts.
يبدأ حقا السحر.
Because the manufacturing process is our organism.
لأن عملية التصنيع هي كائننا الحيّ.
It'll actually begin to digest these wastes
سوف تبدأ حاليّا بهضم هذه النفايات
and, over the next five days,
وعلى مدى الأيام الخمسة المقبلة ،
assemble them into biocomposites.
ستقوم بتجميعها في أجسام حيوية مركبة.
Our entire facility
يتكوّن المصنع لدينا من
is comprised of thousands and thousands and thousands of these tools
آلاف وآلاف وآلاف من هذه الأدوات
sitting indoors in the dark, quietly self-assembling materials --
القابعة داخلا في الظلام ، تقوم وبهدوء بعمليّة تجميع ذاتيّة للمواد --
and everything from building materials
إن كان مواد البناء
to, in this case,
أو، كما في هذه الحالة ،
a packaging corner block.
كتلة تغليف ركنية.
So I've said a number of times that we grow materials.
لقد كرّرت عديد المرات انّنا بصدد زرع المواد.
And it's kind of hard to picture how that happens.
و من الصعب تصوير طريقة حدوث ذلك.
So my team has taken five days-worth of growth,
لذا إتخذ فريقي خمسة أيام من النموّ،
a typical growth cycle for us,
دورة نمو نموذجي بالنسبة لنا ،
and condensed it into a 15-second time lapse.
ومكثف قبل أن تتحول إلى فاصل زمني 15 ثانية.
And I want you to really watch closely
وأريدكم أن تشاهدو عن كثب
these little white dots on the screen,
هذه النقاط الصغيرة البيضاء على الشاشة،
because, over the five-day period,
لأنه، خلال فترة خمسة أيّام،
what they do is extend out and through this material,
ما تفعله هو التمدّد خارج وخلال هذه المادة،
using the energy that's contained in these seed husks
باستخدام الطاقة الواردة في هذه القشور
to build this chitinous polymer matrix.
لبناء مصفوفة البوليمر الكيتيني.
This matrix self-assembles,
هذه المصفوفة ذاتية التركيب ،
growing through and around the particles,
المتنامية من خلال وحول الجزيئات ،
making millions and millions of tiny fibers.
والصانعة للملايين والملايين من الألياف صغيرة.
And what parts of the seed husk we don't digest,
أجزاء قشور البذور التي لا نهضمها ،
actually become part of the final, physical composite.
تصبح في الواقع جزءا من مركب النهائي.
So in front of your eyes, this part just self-assembled.
ذلك وأمام ناظريك، يقوم هذا الجزء بالتجمّع ذاتيّا.
It actually takes a little longer. It takes five days.
يستغرق ذلك في الواقع فترة أطول قليلا. يستغرق خمسة أيام.
But it's much faster than conventional farming.
لكنه أسرع بكثير من الزراعة التقليدية.
The last step, of course, is application.
الخطوة الأخيرة ، بطبيعة الحال ، هي التطبيق.
In this case, we've grown a corner block.
في هذه الحالة ، لقد نمت كتلة ركنية.
A major Fortune 500 furniture maker
صانع أثاث رئيسي
uses these corner blocks to protect their tables in shipment.
يستخدم هذه الكتل ذات الزاويا لحماية موائدهم أثناء الشحن.
They used to use a plastic packaging buffer,
وإستخدامها كعازلات بلاستيكيّة للتغليف،
but we were able to give them the exact same physical performance
لكننا كنا قادرين على منحهم بالضبط نفس الأداء
with our grown material.
مع موادنا التي تنمو.
Best of all, when it gets to the customer,
أفضل ما يمكن الحصول عليه، وعندما تصل إلى العملاء ،
it's not trash.
فإنها لن تكون نفايات.
They can actually put this in their natural ecosystem without any processing,
يمكنهم فعلا وضعها في نظامهم الإيكولوجي الطبيعي دون أية معالجة ،
and it's going to improve the local soil.
وستساهم في تحسين التربة المحلية.
So, why mycelium?
لذلك، لماذا اللّجوء إلى الأفطورة؟
The first reason is local open feedstocks.
السبب الأول هو المواد الأولية المحلية المتاحة.
You want to be able to do this anywhere in the world
نودّ أن نكون قادرين على القيام بذلك في أي مكان في العالم
and not worry about peak rice hull or peak cottonseed hulls,
وأن لا نقلق بشأن ارتفاع أسعار قشر الأرز أو قشر القطن،
because you have multiple choices.
لأن لدينا خيارات متعددة.
The next is self-assembly,
التالي هو التجميع الذاتي ،
because the organism is actually doing most of the work in this process.
لأن هذا الكائن يفعل في الواقع الجزء الأكبر من العمل في هذه العملية.
You don't need a lot of equipment to set up a production facility.
أنت لا تحتاج إلى الكثير من المعدات اللازمة لإقامة منشأة للإنتاج.
So you can have lots of small facilities
بحيث يمكن أن يكون لديك الكثير من المنشآت الصغيرة
spread all across the world.
منتشرة في جميع أنحاء العالم.
Biological yield is really important.
المحصول البيولوجي هو المهم حقا.
And because 100 percent of what we put in the tool become the final product,
ولأن 100 في المئة مما وضعنا في الآلة يتحوّل لمنتج نهائي،
even the parts that aren't digested
حتى الأجزاء التي لم يتم هضمها
become part of the structure,
تصبح جزءا من الهيكل ،
we're getting incredible yield rates.
نحن نحصل على معدلات عوائد لا تُصدق.
Natural polymers, well ... I think that's what's most important,
البوليمرات الطبيعية، أعتقد أن هذا هو الأمر الأهم،
because these polymers have been tried and tested
لأن هذه البوليمرات تمت تجربتها واختبارها
in our ecosystem for the last billion years,
في نظامنا البيئي لمليارات السّنين الماضية،
in everything from mushrooms to crustaceans.
في كل شيء من الفطر إلى القشريات.
They're not going to clog up Earth's ecosystems. They work great.
إنها لن تعطّل النُّظم الإيكولوجيّة للأرض. إنه عمل عظيم.
And while, today,
وبينما ، اليوم ،
we can practically guarantee that yesterday's packaging
نستطيع أن نضمن أن عمليّات التعبئة الماضية
is going to be here in 10,000 years,
ستكون هنا بعد 10.000سنة،
what I want to guarantee
ما أريد أن أضمنه
is that in 10,000 years,
هو أنّه بعد مُضيّ 10.000 سنة،
our descendants, our children's children,
سيتمكّن أحفادنا وأطفال أطفالنا،
will be living happily and in harmony
من العيش في سعادة ووئام
with a healthy Earth.
مع كوكب ينعم بالصحّة.
And I think that can be some really good news.
وأعتقد أن هذا يمكن أن يمثّل بعض الأخبار الجيدة حقا.
Thank you.
شكرا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)